so one of the approaches for eliminating
false dependencies is to duplicate
register values let's see how that would
work we have an instruction here that
adds R2 and R3 and puts the result in R1
then we have R1 minus R5 goes into R4
then we have R4 + 1 goes into R3 then we
have R8 - R9 goes into R4 and sometime
later we have an instruction that uses
R4 here we have what happens in some
cycle let's call it cycle 100 and in the
next few cycles and let's assume that
cycle 100 is when this instruction can
execute now what happens is after we
execute this instruction it can supply
the register value R1 through forwarding
to the next instruction so we have that
this instruction can execute here and
then R4 can be supplied to the next
instruction so it can execute here how
however this instruction which is doing
R8 minus R9 could actually execute here
so the problem with false dependencies
occurs in that R4 is written by this and
also this instruction so let's see which
final value of R4 ends up in the
register so that it is used much later
here well if this is in execution stage
let's say that we have the memory stage
next and the right register stage next
meanwhile this instruction goes through
the m stage here and then write register
here so as you can see we first write
this R4 and only then write this R4
which means that the final value of
register R4 and that is the value that
will be read by this instruction is
actually going to come from this
instruction and that should not be
happening so in order to fix this one
way is to again duplicate register
values so the idea is that when this
instruction writes to the register R4 it
writes to a version of register R4 and
then another value is stored to another
version of R4 but we remember both
versions so that's why it's called
duplication pretty much we don't store
only one value for R4 we store all the
possible values that R4 had and then an
instruction that wants R4 will have to
search among all the possible versions
of R4 to find the one that is before it
but the latest one before it so in this
case we will search for R4 and find this
one and this one and this is the latest
one that we should be using that
requires two versions of R4 to exist
meanwhile this instruction here when it
executes we'll look for versions of R4
and again find that there are really two
versions that it might be using R4 here
and R4 here but because this this one is
coming after this instruction it should
be ignored and thus we use this value so
everything will be correct but it
requires us to keep multiple versions of
each registers which is really
complicated